Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize, 17.92; (9 boxes)
  - George Stinson & Co. "In Remembrance of the One Hundredth Anniversary of the United States." Tinted lithograph, 76 x 58.2 cm. (in Series IV), 1876 (Box 59, Folder 1141)
  - Houghton, Merritt Dana. [Logging camp in Laramie, Wyo.] Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 26.5 x 52 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1142)
  - Houghton, Merritt Dana. "Tatham Ranch, Big Laramie River." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 26.5 x 52 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 59, Folder 1143)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Battle of Atlanta." Chromolithograph, 50.5 x 70 cm. (in Series IV), 1888 (Box 60, Folder 1144)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Battle of Bull Run." Chromolithograph, 50.6 x 70 cm. (in Series IV), 1889 (Box 60, Folder 1145)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Battle of Spotsylvania." Chromolithograph, 50.2 x 66 cm. (in Series IV), 1888 (Box 60, Folder 1146)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Surrender of Admiral Cervera July 3d, 1898. On board the Battleship Iowa." Chromolithograph, 53.2 x 71 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1147)
  - Manhattan Art Company. "Battle of Gettysburg." Color print, visible image 39 x 56.2 cm. (in Series IV), 1893 (Box 60, Folder 1148)
  - Manhattan Art Company. "Washington Centennial Souvenir. Washington Entering New York, and the Portraits of the Presidents of the United States." Tinted lithograph, 56.5 x 70.1 cm. (in Series IV), 1889 (Box 60, Folder 1149)
  - Martin, Thomas Mower. [The artist and his guide in western Canada.] Watercolor, 26 x 56.1 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1150)
  - Moran, Thomas. [The Mountain of the Holy Cross, Colorado.] Print, 77 x 53.6 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1151)
  - N. Currier. "Not Caught. There is Many a Slip Between the Cup and Lip." Lithograph, 46.6 x 61 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1152)
  - Oertel, [Johannes Adam Simon]. "Hambletonian, The Property of W. M. Rysdyk, Esq." Chromolithograph, 52 x 63.7 cm. (in Series IV), 1865 (Box 60, Folder 1153)
  - Proctor, Alexander Phimister. [Mountain sheep.] Etching, plate mark 26.2 x 28.8 cm. on sheet 36.6 x 37.3 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1154)
  - Rees Print & Litho. Co. "Abraham Lincoln's Return Home After His Successful Campaign for the Presidency of the United States, in October, 1860." Chromolithograph, 50.4 x 63.2 cm., (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1155)
  - Reinagle, G. P. "The East India Ship Duke of Buccleuch, (Captn. Alexr. Henning,) in a Hurricane off the Mauritius, attempting to wear." Colored engraving, 48.6 x 62.6 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 60, Folder 1156)
  - Russell, Charles M. [Native American war party on the plains.] Color print, 50.2 x 71 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1157)
  - Stoner, J. J. "Bird's Eye View of the Town of Nantucket State of Massachusetts. Looking Southwest. 1881." Lithograph, 52.2 x 74.7 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1158)
  - Toft, Peter Peterson. [Train going across trestle bridge, with mountain in background.] Watercolor, 34.3 x 51 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1159)
  - Toft, Peter Peterson. [View of Wind Mountain from the left bank of Columbia. Str. James P. Flint. looking downstream.] Watercolor, 34.2 x 50.9 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1160)
  - Tovey, George H. [Bastion of fort.] Watercolor, 20.4 x 52.1 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1161)
  - Waddingham, John Alfred. "Steel Bridge over the Willamette." Watercolor, visible image 35.7 x 50.8 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1162)
  - Weise, A. L. "View of the Ground and Buildings, International Exhibition, Fairmount Park, Philadelphia 1876." Tinted lithograph, 54 x 69 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1163)
  - Unidentified. [Award certificate for Lewis and Clark Centennial American Pacific Exposition and Oriental Fair.] Tinted lithograph, 62.3 x 48 cm. (in Series IV), 1905 (Box 61, Folder 1164)
  - Unidentified. "Democratic National Candidates. For President Grover Cleveland, of New York. For Vice President Allen G. Thurman of Ohio." Lithograph, 55.6 x 72 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1165)
  - Unidentified. [Homestead on a point, overlooking the river, with haystacks, and a butte in the background.] Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 44.1 x 56.2 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 61, Folder 1166)
  - Unidentified. "Olympia. Admiral Dewey's Flagship." Chromolithograph, 50 x 60.2 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 62, Folder 1167)
  - Unidentified. "Ship Caroline Read, Off the Shetland Islands Decr. 6th 1857." Watercolor, 47.9 x 66.5 cm. on sheet 54 x 71.6 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 62, Folder 1168)
  - Unidentified. "Six-Horse Overland Stagecoach. Passing Mount Shasta on the California & Oregon Route." Offset lithograph, 48.6 x 63.5 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 62, Folder 1169)
  - Unidentified. "Topographical Sketch of Fort Vancouver and Environs 1855." Pen-and-ink and watercolor map, 48.5 x 71 cm. (irreg.) (in Series IV) (Box 62, Folder 1170)
  - Unidentified. "Tumwater, near Olympia, Wash. Presented by the Capital Brewing Co. 1899." Tinted lithograph, 57 x 71.5 cm. (in Series IV) (Box 62, Folder 1171)
  - Tavernier, Jules and Paul Frenzeny. "Indian Sun Dance. Young Bucks Proving their Endurance by Self-Torture." Woodcut, 41.5 x 58.2 cm. (in Series V), 1873 (Box 62, Folder 1172)
  - Unidentified. "Hotel Del Monte, Monterey, Cal. The Leading Seaside Resort of the Pacific Coast." Chromolithograph, 47.6 x 53.4 cm. (in Series V), 1883 (Box 62, Folder 1173)
  - Smith, Clarence L. "High School Portland Oregon." Tinted lithograph, 60.1 x 46.2 cm. (in Series V), 1886 Jan (Box 62, Folder 1174)
  - Smith, Clarence L. "The Olympic Range. From Seattle Harbor, Washington Territory." Chromolithograph, 40.7 x 53.9 cm. (in Series V) (Box 62, Folder 1175)
  - Unidentified. "Admiralty Inlet from Port Townsend, Washington." Tinted lithograph, 40.6 x 56 cm. (in Series V) (Box 62, Folder 1176)
  - Unidentified. "'The Fairhaven' Fairhaven, Washington." Tinted lithograph, 40 x 55 cm. (in Series V), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1177)
  - Unidentified. "Grande Ronde Valley, as seen from La Grande Oregon." Tinted lithograph, 50.8 x 55.5 cm. (in Series V) (Box 63, Folder 1178)
  - Unidentified. "'Hotel Portland' - Portland, Oregon. In Course of Construction, Cost $500,000.00." Tinted lithograph, 40.2 x 55.7 cm. (in Series V) (Box 63, Folder 1179)
  - Kuchel & Dresel. "Los Angeles, Los Angeles County, Cal. 1857." Offset lithograph, 55.9 x 71 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1180)
  - Wellge, H. "Bird's Eye View of Leadville, Colo. 1882." Tinted lithograph, 66.5 x 68 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1181)
  - Hall, G. W. "Custer, Idaho -- 1880." Lithograph, 48 x 63.3 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1182)
  - Brown, Grafton T. "City of Portland, Oregon." Tinted lithograph, 56 x 76 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1183)
  - Brown, Grafton T. "City of Portland, Oregon 1865." Offset lithograph, 53.5 x 73.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1184)
  - Unidentified. [Goldendale, Washington Territory.] Lithograph, 49.1 x 64.5 cm. (in Series VI), 1886 (Box 63, Folder 1185)
  - Glover, E. S. "View of New Tacoma and Mount Rainier, Puget Sound, Washington Territory. Terminus of the Northern Pacific Railroad." Tinted lithograph, 48.5 x 74 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1186)
  - Unidentified. "Vancouver, Wash. 1889." Lithograph, 47.3 x 61 cm. (in Series VI), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1187)
  - Hallock, A. B. "Map of Portland." Pen-and-ink and wash map, 49.5 x 60 cm. (in Series IV), 1855 (Box 63, Folder 1188)
  - W.B. Obenauer & Co. "Map of Marion County Oregon." Lithograph, 61 x 61 cm. (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1189)
  - Decourcy, B. W. "Map of Dundee Place. The Supplementary Addition to the Hastings Third Addition to Port Townsend, Wash." Chromolithograph, 48.5 x 63.4 cm. (in Series VII) (Box 63, Folder 1190)
  - Deed of lots of land in the city of Portland, Oregon from George W. Higgins to Henry Sampson and Harley McDonald (in Series VIII), 1852 Jun 7 (Box 63, Folder 1191)
  - Atkinson, John. "C.S.N. Co's Steamer Capital Master." Photograph of an oil painting, 26.2 x 47 cm. on mount 40.4 x 56 cm. (in Series VIII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1192)
  - Gardiner, R. H. "Ship Tillie E. Starbuck, Taking Pilot Off Point Lynas, Irish Channel." Photograph of an oil painting, 23.5 x 34 cm. on mount 35.2 x 42.9 cm. (in Series VIII), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1193)
  - Unidentified. Photograph of Yankee Jim's, Placer County, California, in 1857, drawn from nature and lith. by Kuchel & Dresel, 13.6 x 24.5 cm. (in Series VIII) (Box 63, Folder 1194)
  - Unidentified. Photoreproduction of drawings of Crow papooses, 34 x 41 cm. (irreg.) (in Series VIII), c.1909 (Box 63, Folder 1195)
  - "Fort Dalles, Columbia River, looking down." Three panoramic watercolors, 23.6 x 91.5 cm. (in Series I), 1857 (Box bsd, folder 1196)
  - Bachelder, John Badger. "Gettysburg Battlefield." Colored lithograph, 71 x 101 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1197)
  - Carpenter, F. B. "The First Reading of the Emancipation Proclamation Before the Cabinet. From the Original Picture Painted at the White House in 1864." Lithograph, 64 x 91.2 cm. (in Series IV) (Box bsd, folder 1198)
  - Currier & Ives. "A Midnight Race on the Mississippi." Colored lithograph, 63 x 84.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1860 (Box bsd, folder 1199)
  - Currier & Ives. "A Race for the Buckhorns on the Mississippi." Colored lithograph, 63.2 x 84.5 cm. (in Series IV) (Box bsd, folder 1200)
  - Graham, C. "Niagara Falls from Michigan Central Train." Chromolithograph, 48 x 71.2 cm. (in Series IV), 1903 (Box bsd, folder 1201)
  - Hansen, H. W. (Hermann Wendelborg). "The Last of the Maine and Her Men." Chromolithograph, 66.5 x 99 cm. (in Series IV), 1898 (Box bsd, folder 1202)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Battle of Champion-Hills." Chromolithograph, 50 x 68 cm. (in Series IV), 1887 (Box bsd, folder 1203)
  - Kurz & Allison. "Battle of Stone River. Near Murfreesborough, Tenn." Chromolithograph, 63.7 x 57 cm. (in Series IV), 1891 (Box bsd, folder 1204)
  - Meyer, Richard Max. [Native American camp on the Puyallup River, Wn.] Watercolor and gouache, 51.3 x 71.6 cm. (in Series IV), 1894 (Box bsd, folder 1205)
  - Strong, H. A. "Interior of Fort Garry. A vanished scene in the early History of our Country." Chromolithograph, 58 x 85.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1884 (Box bsd, folder 1206)
  - Torgerson, William. "Striden Emellan Monitor Roads d. 9 Mars 1862." Chromolithograph, 55.2 x 76 cm. (in Series IV), 1877 (Box bsd, folder 1207)
  - Valley, J. F. [Two Navy vessels, British and Spanish (?) off an unidentified coast.] Watercolor, visible image 41 x 65.5 cm. (in Series IV) (Box bsd, folder 1208)
  - Walker, James. "Gettysburg. Repulse of Longstreet's Assault." Lithograph, 61 x 106 cm. (in Series IV), 1876 (Box bsd, folder 1209)
  - Unidentified. "The City of Richmond, Indiana." Tinted lithograph, 70.5 x 101 cm. (in Series IV), 1884 (Box bsd, folder 1210)
  - Unidentified. "Sheridan's Charge at Winchester." Chromolithograph, 51 x 71 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1211)
  - Unidentified. "U.S.S. Charleston." Watercolor painted on silk, 48 x 66 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1212)
  - Unidentified. "Victoria, B.C. 1889." Tinted lithograph, 71 x 107 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1213)
  - Burgess, Geo. H. "San Francisco in 1849." Chromolithograph, 46 x 91.5 cm. (in Series VI), 1894 (Box bsd, folder 1214)
  - Koch, Augustus. "Bird's Eye View of the City of Moscow, Latah County, Idaho. 1897." Chromolithograph, visible image 59 x 79 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1215)
  - Unidentified. "Perspective Map of the City of Helena, Mont. Capital of State, County Seat of Lewis & Clarke Co. 1890." Tinted lithograph, 70.6 x 106.6 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1216)
  - Castleman & Talbot. "Astoria, Clatsop Co., Oregon. The Proposed Terminus of the North Pacific R.R." Tinted lithograph, 52 x 68 cm. (in Series VI), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1217)
  - Unidentified. "Bird's Eye View of Pendleton. Umatilla County, Ore." Chromolithograph, 59.5 x 78 cm. (in Series VI), [ca. 1890] (Box bsd, folder 1218)
  - Smith, C. L. "Portland, Oregon. The Metropolis of the Pacific Northwest." Tinted lithograph, visible image 26.5 x 79 cm. (in Series VI), 1888 (Box bsd, folder 1219)
  - Kuchel & Dresel. "Portland, Multnomah County, Oregon 1858." Offset lithograph, 44 x 69.7 cm. (in Series VI) (Box 63, Folder 1220)
  - Mutual L. & L. Co. "Birds Eye View of Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition and Oriental Fair, Portland, Oregon." Chromolithograph, 71.1 x 116.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1221)
  - Unidentified. "Portland, Oregon. Metropolis of the Pacific Northwest." Chromolithograph (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1222)
  - Kuchel & Dresel. "Salem, Marion County, Oregon. 1858." Colored lithograph, visible image 50 x 67.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1223)
  - "Bird's Eye View of Aberdeen. Gray's Harbor, Wash. 1900." Chromolithograph, 61 x 96.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1224)
  - Unidentified. "Fairhaven, Washington, 1891." Tinted lithograph, 71 x 107 cm. (in Series VI), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1225)
  - Glover, E. S. "Bird's Eye View of the City of Olympia, East Olympia and Tumwater, Puget Sound, Washington Territory, 1879." Tinted lithograph, 51 x 80 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1226)
  - Glover, E. S. "Bird's-Eye View of the City of Seattle, Puget Sound, Washington Territory, 1878." Tinted lithograph, visible image 52.6 x 84.4 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1227)
  - Unidentified. "Seattle, 1889." Tinted lithograph, 60 x 95 cm. (in Series VI), 1946 (Box bsd, folder 1228)
  - Wellge, H. "View of the City of Tacoma, W.T. Puget-Sound, County Seat of Pierce Cty. Pacific Terminus of the N.P.R.R. 1884." Lithograph, 45.8 x 90.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1229)
  - Unidentified. "Tacoma 1889." Lithograph, 61 x 95.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1230)
  - Carson, Will. "Tacoma, Western Terminus of the Northern Pacific Railroad." Chromolithograph, 78.5 x 110.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box bsd, folder 1231)
  - Preston, John B. "A Diagram of a Portion of Oregon Territory." Lithograph, 94.5 x 40 cm. (in Series VII), 1851 (Box bsd, folder 1232)
  - Land grant from Charles, Lord and Proprietary of the Province of Maryland to John Howard. Manuscript on vellum, with original seal attached, framed (in Series I), 1728 Feb 27 (Box art, Folder 1233)
  - Best, A. W. [Native American couple on horseback with child by a river.] Oil painting, 39 x 49.4 cm. in frame 52 x 62 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1234)
  - Best, A. W. [Native American on horseback with travois.] Oil painting, 23.6 x 33.2 cm. in frame 34.5 x 44.3 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1235)
  - Best, A. W. "Pueblo of Laguna - New Mexico." Oil painting, 33.9 x 44 cm. in frame 48 x 58.2 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1236)
  - Best, A. W. "Pueblo of San Ildefonse, New Mexico." Oil painting, 60 x 75 cm. in frame 78 x 93 cm. (in Series III), 1929 (Box art, Folder 1237)
  - Best, A. W. [Pueblo scene, shucking corn.] Oil painting, 34 x 49 cm. in frame 45 x 60 cm. (in Series III), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1238)
  - Paxson, E. S. [After the Fight.] Oil painting, 34.5 x 50.3 cm. in frame 50.7 x 66.5 cm. (in Series III), 1911 (Box art, Folder 1239)
  - Paxson, E. S. "Burial on the Plains, 1852." Oil painting, 45.5 x 61.5 cm. in frame 65 x 79.5 cm. (in Series III), 1902 (Box art, Folder 1240)
  - Paxson, E. S. "Crow Indian Camp." Oil painting, 38 x 29.5 cm. in frame 56.5 x 45 cm. (irreg.) (in Series III) (Box art, Folder 1241)
  - Paxson, E. S. [A shot from the cabin.] Oil painting, 55 x 39 cm. in frame 74 x 59 cm. (in Series III), 1901 (Box art, Folder 1242)
  - Amann, Charles R. [Harbor view with sailing ships.] Oil painting, 36.4 x 48.6 cm. in frame 52.7 x 64.9 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1243)
  - [Borg, Carl Oscar? Native American on horseback with packhorse.] Oil painting, 18.4 x 23.4 cm. in frame 28.1 x 33.2 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1244)
  - Chapman, O. F. [Freeport, opposite Seattle. Five frame structures on quay to left, sail boat right foreground.] Oil painting, 28.6 x 48.7 cm. in frame 41.5 x 62 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1245)
  - Comparet, Alexander. [Stagecoach holdup.] Oil painting, 44.5 x 54 cm. in frame 51 x 61 cm. (in Series IV), 1883 (Box art, Folder 1246)
  - Hayes, William P. "Winter - Grant Street." Oil painting, 37 x 47.5 cm. in frame 51 x 61.5 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1247)
  - Hudson, Grace Carpenter. [Little Mendicino.] Oil painting on stretcher, 23 x 18 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1248)
  - Knowles, Joe. [Bear looking over valley.] Oil painting on stretcher, 54.5 x 68.3 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1249)
  - [L., O.?] [Empty wood frame carved with an eagle at top with the dates 1835 and 1888 on either side. At bottom the word "Beaver" is carved within a scroll], 29.5 x 32.3 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1250)
  - Lee, Manning de Villaneuve. "His cutlass broke against mine and fell in pieces at his feet." Oil painting, 90 x 60 cm. in frame 98 x 68 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1251)
  - Price, Clayton Sumner. "Rainy Day." Oil painting, 59 x 75 cm. in frame 67 x 83 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1252)
  - Proctor, Alexander Phimister. [Mountain peak.] Oil painting, 15 x 18 cm. in frame 21 x 24 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1253)
  - Rockwell, Cleveland. "In the Rocky Mountains." Oil painting, 84.6 x 151 cm. in frame 106 x 172 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1254)
  - Sadar, A. [Ship frozen in harbor, with igloos and dogsled in foreground.] Oil painting on stretcher, 55.3 x 86 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1255)
  - Schafer, Frederick Ferdinand. "Sunset on Castle Rock on Columbia Riv. Oregon." Oil painting, 31 x 51 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1256)
  - Schoonover, Frank Earle. "Old Rogers' fierce eyes glittered as he whispered the one word, 'Treasure!'" Oil painting, 90 x 75.6 cm. in frame 98 x 83.4 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1257)
  - [Stanley, John Mix. Self-portrait of artist in woods.] Oil painting, 49 x 38.7 cm. in frame 67.8 x 57.5 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1258)
  - Stuart, James Everett. "Pilot Rock located on the Summit of Siskiyou Mountains." Oil painting, 14.5 x 29.5 cm. in frame 27.5 x 42.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1886 (Box art, Folder 1259)
  - Swaim, Robert. [Native American woman with horse.] Oil painting on stretcher, 30.5 x 24 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1260)
  - Swift, Thomas. [Fort in spring, with figures on horseback.] Oil painting, 27 x 63.5 cm. in frame 37.5 x 74.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1904 (Box art, Folder 1261)
  - Swift, Thomas. [Fort.] Oil painting, 26.5 x 63.3 cm. in frame 37.6 x 74.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1904 (Box art, Folder 1262)
  - Tilburn, E. O. [Battery Park, New York City.] Oil painting on stretcher, 56.6 x 91.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1897 (Box art, Folder 1263)
  - Unidentified. "Custer's Last Fight." Chromolithograph, 79 x 106 cm. in frame 91.5 x 118.5 cm. (in Series IV), 1896 (Box art, Folder 1264)
  - Unidentified. "License frame made of wood from the frame of the Steamer Beaver, Wood frame, 22 x 27 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1265)
  - Unidentified. [Logging camp.] Oil painting, 51.2 x 79 cm. in frame 63.8 x 91.6 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1266)
  - Unidentified. [Mountain peak from the shore of a river, with duck hunters in the foreground.] Oil painting, half circle mat 13 x 24.2 cm. in frame 35.6 x 45 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1267)
  - Unidentified. "North Pacific Industrial Exposition Building, Portland, Oregon, 1889." Chromolithograph, 63.2 x 91.2 cm. in frame 76.5 x 104.5 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1268)
  - Unidentified. "Portland, Oregon 1890. Population 80,000." Watercolor, 54 x 103 cm. in frame 89 x 139 cm. (in Series IV) (Box art, Folder 1269)
  - Unidentified. [Tillamook lighthouse, Oregon.] Oil painting on stretcher, 45 x 61 cm. (in Series IV), n.d. (Box art, Folder 1270)
  - Tiedemann, H. O. "View of Victoria, Vancouver Island." Chromolithograph, 34.8 x 100.7 cm. in frame 51 x 116 cm. (in Series VI), 1860 (Box art, Folder 1271)
  - Unidentified. "Victoria, the Capital of British Columbia." Chromolithograph, 31 x 84 cm. in frame 49.5 x 102 cm. (in Series VI), [ca. 1890] (Box art, Folder 1272)
  - Burgess, Geo. H. "San Francisco in 1849." Chromolithograph, 57 x 104 cm. in frame 74 x 121 cm. (in Series VI), 1894 (Box art, Folder 1273)
  - Stengele, J. W. "Stengele's View of Astoria, Oregon, 1890." Chromolithograph, 60.2 x 96.2 cm. in frame 74.5 x 110.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box art, Folder 1274)
  - Unidentified. "Portland, Oregon, Showing Also East Portland and the Cascade Mountains." Lithograph, 66 x 111 cm. in frame 93 x 143 cm. (in Series VI), 1881 (Box art, Folder 1275)
  - Clohessy & Stengele's. "Portland, Oregon, 1890." Chromolithograph, 79 x 116 cm. in frame 96 x 132 cm. (in Series VI) (Box art, Folder 1276)
  - Unidentified. "Portland, Oregon." Lithograph, 67 x 100 cm. in frame 82 x 115 cm. (in Series VI), 1890 (Box art, Folder 1277)
  - Mutual L. & L. Co. "Birds Eye View of Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition and Oriental Fair, Portland, Oregon." Chromolithograph, 69.5 x 114.5 cm. in frame 100.5 x 145.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box art, Folder 1278)
  - Caughey, Rollin B. "Authorized Bird's Eye View of the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, Seattle, U.S.A., 1909. Opens June 1st closes Oct. 16th." Chromolithograph, 63 x 100 cm. in frame 82.5 x 119.5 cm. (in Series VI) (Box art, Folder 1279)
  - Unidentified. "Harbor View, City of Portland Oregon." Compliments of The Meier & Frank Store, Portland, Oregon. Halftone (in Series VI), 1908 (Box roll, Folder 1280)
  - Morgan, Edward A. "Map of Puget Sound, Washington Territory." Rolled wall map, colored lithograph, 133 x 101.5 cm. (in Series VII), 1875 (Box roll, Folder 1281)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 18, folder 411 (Box 64, Folder 1282)
  - Box 30, folder 556 (Box 64, Folder 1283)
  - Box 30, folder 557 (Box 64, Folder 1284)
  - Box 30, folder 558 (Box 64, Folder 1285)
  - Box 30, folder 559 (Box 64, Folder 1286)
  - Box 30, folder 569 (Box 64, Folder 1287)
  - Box 47, folder 945 (Box 64, Folder 1288)
  - Box 54, folder 1051 (Box 64, Folder 1289)
  - Box 54, folder 1059 (Box 64, Folder 1290)
  - Box 54, folder 1060 (Box 64, Folder 1291)